Hey, how's it going guys? It is John here.
And in this tutorial I'm gonna go through an entire video ad breakdown.
Uh,
this ad specifically has gone super viral for
the client and I wanted to just show you number one, the sequence,
the thought process behind it and the actual timeline.
So you can see how I arranged my clips and a winning viral,
um, format, sequence, timeline. And so on the left,
obviously we have our, our video. I'm gonna preview, preview it for you, uh,
on the right, actually have the breakdown here, which, uh,
you can easily follow in the, the sequence.
And so let's just jump straight into it.
But before I get into the actual edit,
the company is called Three Spirit.
They are a non-alcoholic alternative for people who are trying to be sober,
who are trying to, uh, like find a a,
an alternative solution that's like natural, but basically this product,
this drink gives you a natural buzz without the hangover, right?
So there's no actual alcohol in it. And um, people love it.
People love the taste. And so the brand itself, you know,
they hired me as an editor, actually at least the agency that was,
that they're working with. And they have a ton,
and I mean a ton of content and a ton of U G c a ton of
lifestyle,
like so much stuff that almost is like overwhelming to be honest.
And um, but they, let me just kind of show you like they have,
they've worked with tons of influencers,
so I had to go through and sift through all their footage and
basically find the gold, find the nuggets.
And I think that's really where the most important part of starting
an edit, especially like this, which is A A U G C mashup of,
of the best clips, is sorting and filtering through all of your footage first.
So I would say like, if I hadn't done that,
then I don't think I would've been able to create as successful of a video if I
hadn't studied the assets that I'm working with. So, as an editor, number one,
you've got to scrub through your footage, collect all the pieces,
and I'll just kinda show you what that looks like from a timeline perspective.
But I basically will start off and, um,
just dump everything into here and then start to like
pick and choose the shots that I like. Um,
and I'll like either raise them up like this on my timeline as okay,
potentially a good shot so I can go back and,
you know, 'cause you wanna do this kind of fairly quickly, right?
You don't want to spend too much time like organizing it yet.
Um,
and then the next step I'll do is I will actually go in here and
start to label them as like, okay, this could be a potential hook. This,
this is a reaction shot, this is a product shot,
this is a call to action. So I'll, I'll use these basic, um,
adjustment layers to kind of create my own categorization.
And this is very helpful. Um,
that way I can just kind of go back and forth between my timeline and locate
the shots that I need. Um, here's another example of that. Um,
you know, hook reactions. These are kind of the things I'm looking for,
like reactions, um, any visual, any, any visual things.
Like if you, if you go through this, you're just gonna find out like, whoa,
these are all like really crazy looking things.
They either say something crazy or it looks crazy.
These are the things that are actually gonna grab attention, right? So, um,
you'll know as an editor, like, I always,
always focus on the hook first.
Like focus on the scroll stopper first because if that's not engaging
enough, then your, your video's gonna flop. And, um, you have to be,
you have to be able to discern that as an editor.
Like what is the most valuable shot that we can use to
grab attention? And it doesn't matter, you know, what you're editing for.
You know, I don't care if it's B two B, I don't care if it's B two C,
I don't care if it's for social media, like attention is the game.
So you need to, if you have a ton of footage, you know you have options,
but if you don't have options, you have to,
you have to create that attention yourself, whether, you know, through movement,
through graphics, through arrows, and yeah.
So let's just jump into this really quick. Um,
yes, here it is.
So first and foremost we have our scroll stopper, okay?
This is number one in our sequence. And basically, um,
I found this clip of this, I'll just play it How
To get tipsy without booze.
Oh yes.
Alright. So as you can see here,
like there's so much happening from this one scene and you know,
this clip I think was just so,
so eye catching because she and her background looks just kind of so colorful
and like over the top how
To get tipsy without booze.
Yes,
You can see her authentic reaction right there. She's actually like surprised.
Um, she's looking at it, she's like, what the heck is going on?
And she actually cusses, right? And so I added a bleep here and an emoji,
um, because it's just even more engaging.
I added this little slow zoom key frame that a little bit just so I can get her
reaction. 'cause you know,
the name of the game is emotions and we're trying to just capture that, right?
We're trying to just pull people in as much as we can and human
emotions are gonna get, get you there. Um, how did, so yeah,
this was init originally a nine by 16,
so I kind of added that blur background behind it. Um, I'll just take this,
scale it out, add AOG and blur behind it. Um,
and so another thing to realize is I do have, these are all my, my hooks.
These are all our, like, we tested all these, uh,
text overlay hooks and we also have voiceover hooks.
So this is how I do my hooks. I'll just layer them all into this first,
like first 3, 3, 4 seconds.
And then I'll either mute them or I will, uh,
disable them as they export.
So having a text overlay with an audio hook to
match it is like double the sensory input, right?
It's double the attention.
So I'm really trying to layer as much information,
as much stimulus stimulation in this first three seconds. Um,
and what we learned is that this video outperformed any,
any other videos that we had. Because this, the hook was just so strong, how to
Get tipsy without booze.
Oh, f**k yes,
I introduced to you three Spirit.
Okay, fantastic. Let's break this down really quick so we have this hook.
All right? And we have the scroll stopper,
which is the intention is to literally just stop the scroll all. So boom,
I've got your attention. Now I want to hook you in. All right? Like,
I think this is very important. Hooks and scroll stoppers are, are,
they mean two different things, at least for me.
And we want to keep them like curiosity.
We wanna keep that curiosity going.
So the headline I chose the internet is going crazy for these magical mocktails.
I have not revealed what this is yet, right?
So that's kind of where the curiosity is like, well what is this thing? Right?
We haven't even mentioned the product yet.
And then here I did a split screen with two people dancing. You're like,
what could potentially this be, right? I
Introduced to you three spirits
And here we go. Like this, this piece of content right here was really nice.
'cause she actually said she introduced the product and I thought that was, um,
it was like a perfect, perfect placement for it.
And this is like her titles and everything too. So, um, that puts us in,
puts us into the product introduction. I introduced you three spirit. Um,
and then what I did here is I wanted to increase the social proof
and the like, just show off that like,
so many people have tried this thing and just kind of build that hype.
Like that's really what I was trying to get at is like, okay,
there's this thing, whoa, people are reacting to it. Um, you know,
hundreds of people are, are like dancing for it and getting excited. Um,
and now let's introduce the product in a big way.
Three spirit, three
Spirit, three spirit,
Boom. Okay, so there's a lot happening here.
I'm introducing the product number one, okay, now I'm showing social proof.
I'm having people say the name three Spirit all at the same time, right?
It's just like extra, uh, extra,
I don't know what you wanna call it. Just Three
Spirit. Three Spirit.
So here is where I actually added their authority, right?
So we go into social proof.
Now I'm showing that they've been featured in other things.
Like we are just hyping the crap out of this product right now. Um,
and so I have all of these different, uh, press seals,
and if you have ads orx, you can get these logos in there real quick.
So that was kind of my, my whole thing. All right,
now we've established that this thing has social proof, has authority,
it it, let's talk about the benefits, right? So now we,
we jump into the benefits and I found that this,
this U g C line was just a killer one. Um, you know,
just going straight into the taste profile. Like,
we found out that like people love the taste of this thing,
and that's one of the biggest reasons why they wanna try it,
or reasons why they continue to buy it as a customer. It,
It's delicious. I didn't think I could be more obsessed with Three Spirit,
but I'm,
And if you could see here, like I, let me just open up this Nest. Um,
I, I added these titles three Spirit,
But I,
And I'm, I, I'm trying to keep the, I'm trying to keep the, uh,
the attention going. Like I'm trying to add a cut.
I'm trying to add something different every time so that, you know,
we're not getting bored like every two seconds, every one to two seconds. Like,
I'm making a cut or I'm changing this, oops.
Or I'm changing the scene in some way.
Three spirit, but I am.
All right, so here is when I actually like talk about the product features.
All right? So
three spirit drinks are non-alcoholic and made of herbal or botanicals.
I needed a quick pick.
And here's when I actually start to break down the,
the three different drinks that they offer because this,
this ad is sending to a collection page, or I'm sorry,
a bundle page where they're trying to sell all three to increase their a o V.
So what I did was just, you know, product one, product two, product three,
and that's basically the format for the next sequence. Made a
Quick pick me up and live minner is perfect for that made with botanicals that
give you a natural buzz. So this one's the social elixir and it has green tea,
it has lion's, Maine tulsi, some B vitamins, and it tastes really good. Calming
My cap is my favorite made with plants like ashwagandha and mallian root at our
so relaxing. So it gives that same benefit as wine just without the hangover.
All right, there's a lot going in there right now.
Let me just lower this because we don't need this right now. Um,
there's definitely a lot happening because this is where we're trying to
convey the key benefits and the key features.
We don't want to like throw anything in there that's,
that's not necessary information. Um, so pick me up
A live,
I wanted to just kind of make this as like in your face as possible. It was
Perfect for that.
There's a lot of variety of U G C that they have.
So I wanted to kind of show the, the breadth of the types of people,
the types of consumers that are taking this product,
but I'm also focusing on what they're saying. And you know,
the ultimate, each product has a different benefit.
So Vener is like more energy based.
So I wanted to show that aspect. I want, I wanted to bring that out in this,
in the narrative.
So Vener is perfect for this. They with botanicals that give you a natural buzz.
So
This, so yeah, natural buzz, like things like these little keywords that are,
you know, triggering them in their head like, oh, that sounds fun.
So this one's the social elixir and it has green tea, it has lions name tulsi,
some B vitamins and it tastes really good.
So one thing about this shot right here is I'm actually, you know,
I'm using her testimonial as the actual voiceover.
Um, but because you know, it's a testimonial as a testimonial,
it's not that exciting. Um,
I overlay it with a ton of different B-roll shots that are related to this
product just to kind of keep it interesting.
You're allowing the narration to happen, but you're not,
you're visually being stimulated at the same time.
Like you can see the cuts right here. Like there's,
It had green tea, it had lion.
This is another little thing that I found was cool,
which was like adding the ingredients to the bottom there,
just kind of happening at the same time.
I'm also speeding up my clips a lot, as you can tell right here.
This one is 600% sped up green tea.
It has lions
Just because I can, like, I can get more outta the footage that way.
T some B vitamins and it tastes really good.
Okay, so moving on to product three. You know, introducing the product
Is my favorite.
Completely different vibe. This product specifically is to like,
make you chill out. So I wanted the shots to be less, you know, in your face,
less dramatic with
Plants like ashwagandha and ball root are so relaxing,
so gives that same benefit as wine just without the hangover.
And so another thing too is, um,
yeah,
I am using different pieces of of U G C lines to create this story.
I think this is the, um, this is the,
the key is like finding a story within the U G C if you're doing a U G C mashup
like this. So moving on,
hang on. We've gotten through product benefit one, two, and three. Um,
next I'm gonna throw in authority in there as well.
So if you have any opportunity to, um, to include authority,
I highly, highly recommend it. If there's any press features,
if there's any interviews, if there's anything you've, you know,
been featured on a magazine or a news article or um,
on a, you know, TV show, this stuff,
people really respond to that because they trust it.
And so if they've seen that you've had some sort of publicity,
like leverage that as much as you can. And it,
in this case, you know, they've been ranked for having award-winning flavor.
And that's one thing that I wanted to just kind of like drill home.
These guys have done the work
Feels like Christmas in a box.
They've really mastered the mixing of adaptogenic herbs to give you that buzz
without the alcohol. Know
That I'm putting good things in my body as opposed to booze.
It gives me that oo that I'm looking for. It's delicious. I am
Super psyched about mocktails. Now,
who would've thought I highly recommend Three Spirit.
Alright, so the final part to this video is A U G C,
social proof, social proof mashup. Because there's so much, you know,
U G C that they have so many testimonials. Um,
I wanted to make each one specific to a particular
objection or a particular pain point or benefit. Um,
and just kind of get that variety of,
of perspectives about the product that's going to trigger something in their
mind. Like, hey,
like if it's one piece of a line that they say that resonates with the customer
or the viewer, like that's, that's all the reason that they're gonna buy.
So we want to create that opportunity as much as possible for the wide
audience. And um, yeah, that's just really what it comes down to. Feels like
Christmas in a box. They really,
So another thing here is I added this call to action,
you know, overlay.
And this is a really good opportunity because most of the people, you know,
they're not gonna make it this far into the video. If they have,
you want to nudge them in the right direction, right?
So there's a lot happening in this product overlay right here. Um,
so you can see I have the bundle here. I have, um,
call to action try three Spirit. I have the actual offer,
free shipping on orders over 90 bucks.
I have another call to action with an arrow pointing down because the C t A is
down here in this corner on Facebook. Um, there's just a lot and it's, it's,
I'm trying to get as much information to the viewer I kind of subconsciously
so that they can take action and when they do take action,
it's gonna be a good reason to do it. So to give you
That,
Know that I'm putting good things in
My body. Yeah. So this, you know, this is your standard mashup of,
of different testimonials,
but I wanted to include like different faces and different reactions like about
Mocktails. We would've thought, I highly recommend Three Spirit.
I always like to end it with like a recommendation.
So it feels like it's a solid end mocktails. Now we
Would've thought, I highly recommend Three Spirit.
And then lastly, I had the call to action, you know, just a stall,
a simple image, lifestyle image that they have or product photography, image,
um, and a call to action here. And essentially that's it.
So this whole, you know, sequence was definitely,
I would say a more complex one. Um,
this is definitely useful if you have a lot of different assets.
If you have press, if you have a lot of U G C, if you have lifestyle,
if you have, you know, this is a brand that is investing a lot in their content.
And so if you have a client, if you work with somebody who, who does like this,
this I would totally follow. Like you can run this ad anywhere,
whether it's Facebook or, or YouTube, um, or probably not TikTok.
TikTok, you'd have to probably edit this down to be more toy.
'cause this is more of like a, you know, it's a, it's a mashup, I would call it.
Like, we call these things that like viral mashups. Um, but it's,
it's a hype video, right? So that's, that was the entire video.
Uh, I hope you hope you gained some, some value from this one.
And I will break down a second viral video for you in the next video.
All right, thanks guys for watching.